[{"question":". Male gametophyte of angiosperms/monocots","a":"Microsporangium","b":"Nucellus","c":"Microspore","d":"Stamen","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"The male gametophyte (microgametophyte) in","a":"Tetrad","b":"Nucellus","c":"Megaspore","d":"Microspore","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"somatic cell, there are 16 chromosomes.  What will be the number of chromosomes in the  pollen","a":"16","b":"8","c":"24","d":"32","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"6. As a pollen tube grows into the female organ, the","a":"Sperm nacleus","b":"Generative nucleus","c":" Tube","d":"Pollen nucleus","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Central cell of embryo sac contains","a":"single haploid nucleus","b":"two haploid polar nuclei","c":"one diploid fusion or secondary mucleus","d":"Either (b) or (c)","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"dicot embryo, the radicle is formed by","a":"epibanal tier of embryo","b":"hypobasal tier of embryo","c":"hypophysis of suspensor","d":"terminal cell of suspensor","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Dicot embryo consists","a":"radicle and plumale","b":"radicle, plumule, cotyledons and sometimes","c":"radicle, plumule, cotyledons and tegen","d":"radicle, plummule, cotyledons, tegmen and","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Growth of pollen tube is:  ","a":"Apical","b":"Basal","c":"Intercalary","d":"Diffused","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Tapetum present in the microsporangial wall","a":"Tapetum present in the microsporangial wall","b":"Endothecium and middle layers","c":"Epidermis and middle layers (d) Middle layers and sporogenous","d":"Middle layers and sporogenous","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Pallen tube is covered","a":"Pectocellulose","b":"Sporopollenin","c":"Cellulose","d":"Lignocellulose","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Polygonum type of embryo sacitypical female gametophyte of angiosperms is:","a":"7-celled, 7-nucleute","b":"7-celled, 8-nucleate ","c":"8-celled, 7-nucleate","d":"8-celled, 8-nucleate","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Ovule is inverted with body fused to funicle,  micropyle lying close to hilum and facing the","a":"Hemitropous","b":"Orthotropous","c":"Anatropous","d":"Campylotropous","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Bamboo reproduces by:","a":"Rhizomes","b":"Tubers","c":"Corms","d":"Stolons","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"When the pollen tube enters the ovule through  the integuments, the phenomenon is known","a":"Isogamy","b":"Porogamy","c":"Mesogamy","d":"Chalarogamy","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"self pollination, flower must be","a":"Unisexual","b":"Bisexual","c":"Monosexual","d":"Asexual","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The phenomenon of two flowers, one having long stamens and short styles, and other having","a":"Allogamy","b":"Heterostyly","c":"Dicliny","d":"Herkogamy","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which of the following pair has haploid  structures?  ","a":"Nucellus and antipodal cells.","b":"Antipodal cells and egg cell","c":"Antipodal cells and megaspore mother cell.","d":") Nucellus and primary endosperm nucleus","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"In angiosperms, female gametophyte is","a":"Synergids","b":"Carpel","c":"Egg","d":"Pallan sine","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":". Intine of pollen grain","a":"Callose","b":"Pecto-cellulose","c":"Cellulose","d":"Fat-like sporopollenin","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Abundant occurrence of fossilised pollen grains","a":"Lignocellulose","b":"Sporopollenin","c":"Pectocellulose","d":"Pectolignin","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Tapetal cells are","a":"Haploid","b":"Polyploid","c":"Diploid","d":"Triploid","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Embryo sac is surrounded by a wall of","a":"cells  ","b":"transfer","c":"membrane of","d":"egg","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Vegetative nucleus occurs","a":"All flowering plants","b":"All seed plants","c":"All vascular plants","d":"embryophytes","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Cross-pollination is preferred over self pollination","a":"results in better offspring","b":"new varieties are formed  hybrid plants become sterile in coming  (c) it is easy  (d) parthenogenesis can be induced","c":"easy","d":"parthenogenesis","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Unisexuality of flowers prevente","a":"geitonogamy but not xenogamy","b":"autogamy and gritonogamy","c":"autogamy but not geitonogamy","d":"both geltonogamy and xenogamy","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Unisexuality of flowers prevente","a":"geitonogamy but not xenogamy","b":"autogamy and gritonogamy","c":"autogamy but not geitonogamy","d":"both geltonogamy and xenogamy","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following statement is true about","a":"It is the innermost layer of anther wall","b":"(b) Cells of tapetum are large in size and has more than one diploid nuclei or","c":"the formation of  sporopellenin","d":"All of the above","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"a seed of maize, scutellum is considered as","a":"protects the embryo","b":"contains food for the embryo","c":"absorbs food materials and supplies","d":"converts itself into a monocot","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Apple  58. The largest cell in a embryo","a":"Egg","b":"Central cell","c":"Synergid","d":"Antripodal cell","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Xenogamy is also known","a":"Autogamy","b":"Cross pollination","c":"Self pollination","d":"Cleistogamy","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Wind pollinated flowers","a":"small petals and sticky pollen","b":"petals and light pollen","c":"coloured and large petals with large","d":"petals and heavy","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Function of suspensor of embryo","a":"absorption of nourishment","b":"push the embryo into nutritive endosperm","c":"formation of secondary","d":"All of the above","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Wall of mature pollen grain consists","a":"Ektexine and endexine","b":"Tapetum and endothecium","c":"Exine and intine","d":"Foot and baculate layer","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Isogamy is","a":"fusion of male and female gametes","b":"fusion of physiologically and morpho","c":" effect of low tempera  71.","d":"None of the above","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The insect pollinated pollen grain, tapetum","a":"Spotopollenin","b":"Cellulose","c":"Pectin","d":"Pollen kit","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"the time of anther dehiscence","a":"middle layers develop fibrous thickenings","b":"epidermis degenerates","c":"endothecium develops fibrous thickenings.","d":"endothecium","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Apomixis","a":"development of plar","b":"development of p","c":"inability to perceive","d":"effect of low tempera","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which of the following floral parts forms pericarp","a":"Nucellus","b":"Outer integument","c":"Ovary wall","d":"Inner integument","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"3-celled stage of the mature male gametophyte","a":"before pollination ","b":"after pollination  epidermis, endothecium,  (c) during fertilisation (d) after fertilisation","c":"during fertilisation","d":"after fertilisation","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Endothecium layer of anther lobes is present","a":"outside the epidermis","b":"inner to epidermis","c":"the innermost layer","d":"the middle region","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"3-celled stage of the mature male gametophyte","a":"before pollination ","b":"after pollination  epidermis, endothecium,  (c) during fertilisation (d) after fertilisation","c":"during fertilisation","d":"after fertilisation","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which of the following floral parts forms pericarp","a":"Nucellus","b":"Outer integument","c":"Ovary wall","d":"Inner integument","hint":"","correct":"c"}]